Eric Lachenmeier

Palo Alto, CA 94301 (650) 283-8835 eric.lachenmeier@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ericlachenmeier

SUMMARY

Senior design engineer and entrepreneur. Coding skills include Ruby, Rails, HTML, & CSS. Product design skills using SolidWorks, AutoCAD, and FEA. Other skills include financial modeling, ISO certification, project management, Software/IT knowledge includes Adobe CS, ERP, CRM, SQL, CPM, DBs and Quick Books. Product design experience includes scientific instrumentation, optics, semiconductor processing equipment, software and services.

EXPERIENCE

Lachenmeier consulting: Product Development, Finance, Engineering, Marketing, Strategic Planning, Palo Alto, CA Fund Raising 2009 to present

COMPLETE GENOMICS INC. Low cost, high throughput complete human DNA sequencing service Vice President, Corporate Development

Mt. View, CA 2006 to 2009

- Developed a service-based business model leveraging a proprietary DNA sequencing technology developed inhouse.
- Led the search for a corporate headquarters and managed the build-out and move to the new facility
- Co-authored a NIST grant proposal that resulted in winning a 5 year, \$12M federally funded grant. Hired and managed a 12 person development team.
- Negotiated and closed million dollar service contracts with major Pharma, Biotech, and Research organizations.

ALLEGRO BIOSCIENCES, Internet-based scientific research, virtual laboratory and data management San Diego, CA Founder 2000 to 2002

- Developed and launched a web-based research tool to design and conduct experiments on the web
- Developed software architecture, managed software team, and recruited a network of service providers
- · Led sales and marketing activities
- Led investor road shows in Europe and the US, raised seed round of financing,
- Negotiated a Series A term sheet
- Authored and filed a broad business process patent

INCYTE GENOMICS, A pioneer in genetic research, now Incyte Corporation, publicly traded as INCY Vice President, Technology Development

Palo Alto, CA 1996 to 2000

- Led the development of numerous laboratory robotic systems, fixtures and labor and time saving tools
- Led the development and deployment of two generations of DNA seguencing instruments
- Created the firms first engineering department
- Built and led a world-class, cross-functional technology development team consisting of biologists, software and mechanical engineers, and chemists

LYNX THERAPEUTICS, A provider of genetic profiling services, merged with Solexa, now Illumina Start-up Engineering Manager and Scientist

Hayward, CA 1995 to 1996

- Worked as an engineer and scientist, designing optical imaging systems and fluorescence detection instruments
- Designed and built microscopy imaging instrumentation with a multi-disciplinary team of scientists and engineers

Eric Lachenmeier Page 2

APPLIED BIOSYSTEMS, DNA Analysis Systems: PCR, DNA sequencing and synthesis

Foster City, CA 1988 to 1995

- Project Leader and Inventor, ABI 310 DNA Analyzer, a system that has created revenues exceeding \$250M
- Identified new products based on customer needs and the commercial potential of emerging technologies
- · Developed broad technology platforms that could be leveraged in multiple formats and applications
- Led the development of the world's first commercial capillary DNA sequencer/fragment analyzer
- Recruited and managed a high-performance team of chemists and engineers.
- Inventions included optics, Peltier cooled CCD, separation gels, electro kinetic DNA stacking technology, and the control & analysis software
- · Oversaw the overall instrument design including software and hardware details and documentation

Inventor ABI 377 DNA Sequencer

Inventor of a major DNA analysis platform used to sequence the Human Genome (Patent 5,543,026 August 1996). Generated revenues in excess of \$400 million

BECKMAN INSTRUMENTS

Palo Alto, CA

Design Engineer: Biomek 1000 - laboratory robotics, plastic consumables. Blood analysis product design 1986 to 1988

HEWLETT PACKARD

Palo Alto, CA

Production Engineer: Microwave instrumentation production engineer, process improvement (SQC, JIT)

1984 to 1986

EDUCATION

THE WHARTON SCHOOL, UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA Master of Business Administration, Finance Major

Philadelphia, PA 2004

MASSACHUSSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering

Cambridge, MA 1984

PROFESSIONAL RECOGNITIONS and INTERESTS

- Volunteer for the CASA foster child program 2012
- Session chairman and frequent participant at biotechnology and investment conferences
- Stanford University Office of Technology Licensing, 2001: Out-licensing Advisor for University gene portfolio
- Human Genome research grant reviewer, 1998, U.S. Department of Energy, Washington DC
- Multiple patents in the areas of DNA analysis and engineered devices
- Designed and built 2 custom houses: architect, general contractor, electrician, and plumber